Leo Miler

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil



johnson.soma@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/johnlemile

Summary

Experienced Quality Assurance Engineer with over ten years of experience working to ensure the highest quality outcomes possible. Adept in providing suggestions and solutions to improve and enhance productivity.

Developed software requirements and test matrixes, modifying software test scope documents used throughout the entire Testing Lifecycle process. Responsible for hiring QA & Development Team members and Mentoring QA Engineer team members.

- Successfully developed and executed test plans, procedures, use cases and test scripts, and provided in-depth analysis to create and rollout new software.
- Improved product usability by creating feature enhancement requests, as well as performing systems analysis on existing products where documentation was lacking.
- Facilitated Change Control Board meetings, team staff and technical meetings as a key thought leader within the organization.

Experience



Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Instituto de Pesquisas Eldorado

Apr 2020 - Present (7 months +)

Software Quality Analyst Engineer at HP 3D Software Division.

General activities: 3D printers projects focus.

- Provide test estimates and track QA tasks progress;
- Design, write, and execute test scenarios by established test design techniques and all applicable documentation;
- Uncover, document, and track product defects in defect tracking system;
- Work closely with developers to release process and procedures;
- Adapt, collaborate, and communicate effectively with Agile Scrum team.

TOOLS:

- Functional/Automated Testing: internal environments, Java & Maven/IntellyJ and Javascript & Cypress, Postman, Azure (cloud framework).
- Analysis and Defect Management: JIRA/Confluence.

© Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Object Edge Inc

May 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 11 months)

Software Quality Analyst Engineer at Object Edge Inc. Brazil Division.

General activities: eCommerce projects focus.

Provide test estimates and track QA tasks progress;

- Design, write, and execute test scenarios by established test design techniques and all applicable documentation;
- Uncover, document, and track product defects in defect tracking system;
- Work closely with developers to release process and procedures;
- Adapt, collaborate, and communicate effectively with Agile Scrum team.

TOOLS:

- Functional/Automated Testing: OCC tools environments, TestCafe (javascript single site QA automation Framework), Cucumber (BDD and UAT automation Frameworks), Postman and SoapUI (API tests Framework), OWASP Zap (Security tests Framework), Jenkins (integrated automation/reports Framework).
- Analysis and Defect Management: JIRA/Confluence.



Quality Engineering Analyst

Resource IT Solutions

Jun 2017 - Apr 2018 (11 months)

Quality Assurance at DELL Porto Alegre/RS.

General activities: EC/GTT/AERO/Deployment/Transfer teams.

- Provide test estimates and track QA tasks progress;
- Design, write, and execute test cases (user scenarios) using established test design techniques and all applicable documentation;
- Uncover, document, and track product defects in defect tracking system;
- Work closely with developers to release process and procedures;
- Adapt, collaborate, and communicate effectively with Agile Scrum team.

TOOLS:

- Functional/Automated Testing: Visual Studio, Microsoft Test Manager, SoapUI, SQL Developer
- Analysis and Defect Management: Visual Studio (TFS)



Tech Analyst

Datasys STARH - Tecnologia em Administração de RH

Aug 2013 - Jun 2017 (3 years 11 months)

Worked with Human Resources ERP application designed with Delphi and Oracle 9g, 10g and 11g.

- Client Functional Attendance and Production Environment Quality Assurance/Quality Control;
- Provide test estimates and track FA and QA/QC tasks progress;
- Design, write, and execute test cases (user scenarios data) using established test design techniques and all applicable documentation;
- Uncover, document, and track product defects in defect tracking system;
- Work closely with developers to release process and procedures;
- Work next to the clients for tracking, delivering and implementing ERP solution updates.

TOOLS:

- Functional/Automated Testing: Visual Studio 2017, BadBoy, SQL Developer
- Performance Testing: Visual Studio 2017, WebLoad, DevTools, LightHouse.
- Analysis and Defect Management: TestLink, Mantis, Constat Qualitor

Administrative Analyst HR

Expresso Javali SA Apr 2012 - Jul 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Human Resources Analyst SR

CTZ Consultoria & Informática Ltda. Jan 2010 - Mar 2012 (2 years 3 months)

Human Resources Analyst PL

PAMPA Vigilância e Segurança Ltda. Apr 2009 - Aug 2009 (5 months)

Education

Anhanguera Educacional

Bachelor's Degree, Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas 2013 - 2015

Bachelor's Degree, Psicologia 2004 - 2008

Skills

Agile Testing • Test Automation • Quality Engineering • ERP • Scrum • Oracle SQL Developer • Microsoft SQL Server • SQL • Oracle • IT Projects Managment